Togashi
Would you like a home-cooked lunch?
I woke up at 5 this morning to start it
It was my first time cooking anything
Hey, hold on a sec
You didn't make anything for me, did you?
Why don't you give it to the dude you're actually trying to impress?
Okay, fine, you want me to eat it, I'll eat it
Togashi
I wasn't kidding
We need to have a talk
Let me out of here! I don't want to go to Musashino! Don't make me!
Dude, you gotta chill out!
Hey, Tachibana, did you mean what you said?
You don't want to play the next match? Are you serious?
Dude, why? You remember what Kanita said?
We can't just let that trash stand!
Besides, Musashino is your old team!
Don't you have a lot of friends from back in junior youth who still play?
Now's your chance to show them how you've grown!
How can you not be excited about that?
If I had anything to show them...
I don't get it.
I mean, I still have friends I played with back in Ehime.
Someday, I hope they get the chance to watch me play.
I would show off my skills.
And if we ended up playing on the same field,
that would be the ultimate dream.
And speaking of Musashino youth,
I've heard their current manager is one of the best out there.
Huh?
Musashino's not even a J youth team.
It's just a regular youth team.
Which means they're way behind all you guys.
At least in terms of potential.
And the kind of environment they're in.
But still, ever since manager Satake got promoted from the junior youth setup,
the players are out there looking like those factors don't even matter game after game.
Pretty exciting, huh?
He came from junior youth.
So that's the same manager Tachibana used to play under.
Been training our asses off all year.
The whole team did.
Under manager Satake's guidance.
Ugh.
Ngh!
Must be nice not to have a manager who forces his players to change positions out of frickin' nowhere!
What's going on?
Were you having vengeful thoughts about my brother?
If so, you need to stop.
Yeah, sure.
What are you doing here anyway, Hana?
I'm chaperoning!
Duh!
Great.
This traffic better let up before I miss my next class.
I see what's going on here.
Huh?
Not that I blame you.
When you give him that pic, it's gotta be perfect.
Hashito and I...
We're friends, that's all.
Tachibana!
Huh?
Hi, manager Satsake.
Hey, did you come here to watch us?
What? Manager?
So that's him.
Strategizing, huh?
For your game next week?
No.
I've got nothing to strategize about.
I asked them not to play me.
So, yeah.
Sounds like you're struggling a bit.
That's a good sign.
You chose your path knowing what lay ahead.
So if you're struggling some right now, then that tells me you've chosen the right path.
I'm glad to see you're working so hard.
Take care.
You okay, bro?
That guy's intimidating.
For real.
It's incredible.
The way he's made a team of nobodies as strong as they are.
You've been coached by him, so what's the deal?
What's the deal?
Remember what Nakano said?
Musashino's made up of dudes who wanted to play J-Youth and weren't good enough in the end.
And now they're undefeated in Tokyo's top league?
And on a six-game winning streak?
I mean, you gotta give it up.
That guy knows what he's doing.
Are they double pressing right off the bat?
Okay, that was a bit desperate.
Their press is fast.
And it looks like they've always got two players pressuring the opponent.
So they rely on numbers to win the ball and to make up for what they lack individually.
Mitsuya!
Three players?
I get pressing high, but come on.
That's a little too much.
I mean, look at that space.
They're leaving it wide open.
He reacted so fast.
No.
Before the pass was ever hit, that midfielder went for it.
He ran right toward the space.
The space wasn't there by accident.
It was a setup.
In order for them to intercept the ball, they had to create a distraction and steer the pass away.
And it worked.
They got it!
Yep, that's their signature technique.
Basically a super high press.
A swarm of bees.
They surround the player and steal the ball.
I mean, a high press in itself isn't rare or anything.
It's the super part that's scary.
I know.
There is this phrase Satsuke would always say.
Take risks.
Listen up.
It's not a bad thing if you aren't the best players.
All that really means is you have nothing to lose.
You guys can leave a space.
Keep the high press on.
They're not expecting strategy from you.
If the other team is better than you man to man, they'll have more possession.
This makes you nervous, so you retreat to your own half to defend your goal.
But think about it for a moment.
Will doing that intimidate the other team in any way?
Of course it won't.
You have to take risks.
When the opponent can't predict your moves, that's when they start to feel threatened.
You've got to keep them guessing.
So don't ever hide behind the safest move.
There's no hesitation.
Each of them knows what they're supposed to do.
It looks so effortless.
Gotta say, it's such an all-or-nothing move.
If a single thing goes wrong, the other team could score.
Yeah, that's true.
But it's not just this one move that makes the team successful.
No, it's...
It's the way they play.
They face their weaknesses instead of denying them.
They know exactly what to expect from each person on their team,
and what each of them lacks individually.
It's their mental strength that makes it possible.
I can't believe how incredibly well the team is doing this year.
Ten of them completely know their roles in the field.
That's about as close to perfect as it gets.
Of course...
There's always that one.
He didn't fall?
Compared to them?
We're a giant mess of weakness and hesitation.
They play without fear.
We lack that kind of strength.
Their team plays like a single unit.
Yeah, but...
What about him?
Does Kanita know he's part of a single unit?
What's wrong with you?
Get your hands off of my butt!
Sorry.
Uh...
I just wanted to say that I'm leaving now, since the game is over.
You are?
But why?
Um...
What do you mean, why?
Is there something you need me to do?
Just wondering if you really have to go.
Wait, what?
I haven't seen you in a while.
And, uh...
I don't know when I'll see you again.
Yeah, that's true.
So, I don't know.
Maybe we could, like, hang out or something.
It's...
What do you want to talk about?
Right?
You need help with your diet plan?
I can do that.
I mean, if you want.
But we can also talk about soccer.
Ah!
I mean, if you want.
But we can also talk about soccer.
Yeah, I call Anrii.
She knows I'm going to meet you in a while.
Maybe I am going to meet you in a while.
I wanna meet you in a while.
Is there something you need me to do?
Just wondering...
Just wondering if you really have to go.
Wait, what?
What?
I haven't seen you in a while.
And, uh...
I don't know when I'll see you again.
Yeah, that's true.
So, I don't know.
way more about that than me anyway we should be getting back too i'd rather not hang around here
for long so each it all what hi miyako we have to talk not here somewhere off field
what's wrong why haven't you kept in touch well what the heck man i didn't know you had a
girlfriend she's my sister this is miyako tachibana we're twins she plays for the tokyo
musashino ladies you never mentioned anything about a twin before oh i haven't
hmm don't want to talk to me that's fine but you really need to answer when mom or dad call you
look i told you it just doesn't feel right until i'm a regular starter for asperion i
idiot you have such a warped idea of what success is and you always have
now what kind of man doesn't talk to his parents when they call
don't worry miss i'll get this heathen straightened out for you trust me
you kidding back it up right now
a lot has changed you are aware of musashino's current standing aren't you
uh yeah they're pretty strong and you know kanida the one who replaced you as forward
well he's a piece of work nobody can stand him
i mean it you're still a first year you can't talk to your captain like that
hey i'm just stating the facts that's all you're like a sick turtle when you go after the ball
slow mo muto how am i supposed to respect you as my captain when it takes you a million ages just
to pass me the ball don't you want to be strong whatever you're all the way up front and i've never
seen you try to help out with defense if i don't have the ball i can't score you're the ones who are
supposed to be helping me don't you morons get how this works my pinpoint counter-attacks are what
make our high press plays possible so i'll say whatever i damn well want
but i guess i'm expecting too much of you guys unlike in jay youth no one's interested in making
a career out of this right i mean help me understand here fellas what's the point of playing soccer at
this stage in your life if you're giving up on going pro difference between you and me is that i have
what it takes so tell all those other losers to stop talking if they don't have the guts to prove
themselves oh yeah our next match is against esperion we'll see the guy who passed their worthless
tryouts tachibana yep you know who i'm talking about so let's get out there and crush him okay
shut up kanida hey ashito what are you doing still don't get why you failed the tryouts it's because
you weren't good enough i can see it now you can talk but you're this team's weakest player
why the hell are all of you here tachibana wow it's really you
muto mikami it's been a while what did you come out here to spy on us you have the nerve to call me
weak while you're trying to steal our moves are you guys from esperion we don't want any trouble
so please leave what's gotten into you why did you jump out like that that kanida
keeps bugging tachibana
hey it's fine ashito let's go home little aoi i'm surprised you still have the guts to keep talking
trash about me what as of today i've got nine goals to my name which puts me ahead of everyone else in
the entire league and what about you what have you done aoi besides playing a position that you
really suck at or has something changed gonna pretend you've decided you want to be a pro defender now
yeah right don't even try how can you stand on that field without a clue as to what you're doing there
tell me
why didn't i freaking shoot why i want you to know that i've never hated anyone more than you
stupid talentless hillbilly stealing spots on a j youth team in tokyo
i don't know what you're getting all up in my face for tachibana
they should all be grateful to you things got better after you left they got much stronger
and it's all thanks to me say what you want about me but don't you dare insult my friends
take it back right now hey take it easy this isn't like you at all this is exactly what i hate about
you twerps and your stupid get along gang this isn't summer camp you're missing the entire point
i'm just gonna keep getting better all on my own and you'll have your little friends holding
your hands like always we'll see who scores more
how the heck did that epic jerk become a starter
i can't even stand looking at him much less playing soccer with him
honestly i have no idea but just between us
it feels like manager sateke is letting him do whatever
about time you were gone a while you can't be serious
yeah but his teammates just accept that he's like that
and they're getting stronger every day what's wrong did something happen
how can you stand on that field without a clue as to what you're doing there
i wanted to say something back but i froze
did something happen i hate that i do that
i can't stop kanita if i'm always backing down or if he's his own hype gang
he's a nightmare as a ford a ball of raging fire
i can't do anything until i make a change not by myself or with my team
what the heck was that for
i asked you what happened and you just ignored me
well you didn't have to resort to violence and besides you wouldn't understand anyway
i waited for you just like you asked me jerk
and i remembered what i wanted to tell you
kuribayashi saw one of my meal plans and asked me to create some for him
kuribayashi
he'll follow them to the letter and then report back to me about how they're affecting his body
his energy and muscle mass and as an aspiring sports doctor
it's a great chance for me but well i figured i should check with you first
to make sure that it's okay so is it
why ask me
it isn't like you need my permission
it's a great opportunity you should go for it
yeah you're right i will
what the heck why do i feel like something's weird about that
kuribayashi what freaking for
you know i'm actually a little relieved
you used to watch games without any real spark in your eye
but now i know you can at least get angry
you shouldn't worry about whether or not your team beats us
they're strong and they support you
you're right
but i um i talked to my coach
and i asked him not to play me in the next match
huh
hey aoi where's hana
did she happen to give you something today
like what
okay well that's kind of awkward
huh it's from masako
what
what's wrong
yoshitsune is going back to the a team
okay well there goes any chance we have at winning
we know togashi hates kurida's guts
he and takashima already have beef
and now they're throwing kurida in as a replacement
they want to make our lives hell i just know it
i don't know if we're gonna be okay you guys
can we really play with all this drama
hey tachibana
uh yeah
one of my assignments was to interview some of the musishino players today
and every single one of them asked how you were doing
huh
it sounds like you were quite the ace on that team
and that you had been ever since junior youth
also
they said that even though you abandoned them for asperion
they all agreed how grateful they were to you
grateful
that's right
well maybe
unlike those other grumpy forwards i met
the strength you have lies in something completely different
a different kind of strength
from yoshitsune and kaneda
so don't ever compare yourself to them
oh yeah
and they also said they're looking forward to seeing you
when they play against you next week
are you scratching yourself
right in the middle of a touching heart to heart
no something's poking me in the back
tachibana
thank you
i'm grateful to you too
i trust you as a teammate
really
me too
the truth is
i want to play the match with you guys
we're like brothers
the three of us together
we're playing musashino next
and they're undefeated so far
so taking that into account
these are the starters for next week
there are still two positions i haven't assigned yet
but here's the lineup
oh why
what made you choose this lineup
that's how it works
right now
this is our best team
let's do it
let's win
we have to
let's do it
Next time on Awashi, the truly weak one.